for a long time the
news headlines have not stopped showing us numbers
of victims and attacks in Gaza Lebanon
Israel we hear many names never
Palestine but do you know the reason for this
war in this video we will try to make
known the origin of this conflict
going into its
roots for this we will start with the most
basic to know the enemy sides on
one hand we have the state of Israel of
Jewish religion and on the other the state
of Palestine ch which is recognized by very
few countries and in which the vast
majority is of Sunni Muslim religion
both Israelis and Palestinians
claim their right to inhabit the area we
know as Israel the Israelis
claim sovereignty in the city for being
descendants of the Ancient Hebrew people
calling themselves
[Music]
since the first century AD
the Jews have lived in exile
although there was a significant presence of
Jews in what we know as
present-day Israel according to Judaism
and the Bible the land of Israel or Zion
is the land promised by God to the
Jews after the Barba rebellion in the
year 132 to 135 the Jews were
expelled although in  They always
had a nostalgia to return to what
they considered their historic people and
now that we know both peoples let's
jump in time again to the end
of the 19th century Israel was part of the
Ottoman Empire at this time
Zionism was born which was an ideology and
political movement that proposed
establishing a state for the
Jewish people in Palestine this movement
arose in Europe and was founded by
Teodor Herd as a response to the hatred of
Jews that existed in Europe during
those years in summary it sought to give
Jews the right to their
historic territory which was the land of Israel or
Zion hence the word Zionism the
Jews wanted to be in Jerusalem because
God had
promised it to them since 1882 a
massive migration of Jews to
Palestine began in this first migration which was
known as the first aliyah approximately
35,000 Jews arrived in Palestine
the second aliyah arrived
in 1904 when Zionism that we
have talked about became very popular
and many Israelis migrated to Palestine
again however when the
First World War came the
Ottoman Empire fell and the United Kingdom took
control of  Palestine Thanks to the fact that the
United Kingdom was in control of the
territory, Jewish migrations
to Palestine multiplied enormously
because of the discrimination and
prejudice that existed in Europe towards
Jews, which is known as
anti-Semitism, they preferred that they left
Europe to stay there. Therefore, at
that time, the Jews who migrated
to Palestine went from being 8% of
the population in
1882 to 28% in
1936. The following years continued with
five more massive waves of
Jewish emigration and major attacks
between Muslims and Jews broke out, such as the
Hebron massacre. This created great
tensions between both communities,
causing the Jews to create their
own defense force,
also known as the Haganah. A
group of radical Jews called the
Irgun gathered together and began several attacks
against the British in Palestine to
pressure the United Kingdom to create the
state of Israel. Either they did something and
gave them what they wanted, or they would continue with
violence. During World War II,
a new
wave of Jewish emigration from Europe
to Palestine occurred again.  the vast majority trying to
escape the Nazi Holocaust
once the war ended a year
later in
1946 the radical Jewish group Irgun
carried out an attack against the
British command in Palestine
causing 92 deaths this causes the
United Kingdom to finally get tired of being
in the middle of a war of conflicts that
had nothing to do with it so it decides to
withdraw from Palestine the following year
and let someone else resolve the confrontation
then in 19 47 the UN approved a
plan that divided Palestine into two
states giving Muslims and
Jews an extension of land similar
to each one so on May 14,
1948 the state of Israel was proclaimed
in the territory approved by the UN and
what did the Arabs do about this because
two days after the Independence of
Israel the Palestinians supported by
Egypt Syria Lebanon Saudi Arabia and
Transjordan declared war on
the Israelis but the Jews not only did not
lose the war but
managed to increase their territory by more
than 20% of what they had designated by
the UN the Gaza Strip was occupied by
Egypt and the West Bank by Transjordan
as a result of that war in the area
controlled by Israel the Israelis
took their homes from more than 700,000
Arabs and on the other hand in the area
controlled by the Arabs they
expelled the Jews including several
communities that had been established
there for many years in
1956 Egypt nationalized the Suez Canal
and blocked the Straits of Tiran which was
the entry route to the Israeli port And
how did the Jews respond? Well,
allied with the United Kingdom and France, they
invaded the Egyptian
Sinai Peninsula and won their army but the
UN made the Israelis withdraw in
exchange for a pact to create a
demilitarized zone in the Suez Canal,
thus having entry to Israel.
However, in
1967 the UN soldiers, also
called blue helmets, had
withdrawn and the Straits of Tiran were
again blocked by the
Arabs. Egypt, Syria, Iraq, and Jordan
then prepared to attack Israel
in what was known as the Six
Day War, despite being hit by
four  countries Israel won the
war again and invaded the Sinai Peninsula,
the Gaza Strip, the
Palestinian territories of the West Bank and the
Golan Heights that were Syrian in
1973, the Arabs attacked again in the
Yom Kippur War to recover the
Golan Heights and the Sinai Peninsula.
This is where the great powers also came into play. The
United States supported
Israel and the Soviet Union supported the Arabs.
And again, victory went to Israel.
Although it gave in in the negotiations and
returned the Sinai territories to
Egypt. But of course, it would not be
pleasant. In return, Egypt would recognize
Israel, being the first Arab country to
do so and ceasing to be enemies in
terms of the Palestinian territories, it
gave in to returning a part of them, but
not all of them. In 1982, Israel invaded southern
Lebanon to prevent
Palestinian guerrillas from entering its territory.
This Israeli presence continued until
2000 and in 2006, Israel struck
Lebanon to attack the
Ibola militia. The Israelis have continued to go
increasing their land and colonizing more
and more organizing several
Jewish settlements in Palestinian territories this
led to the
first intifada in 1987, a Palestinian uprising
with riots and protests against
Israeli rule. The images that
reached the rest of the world
shocked everyone. Videos and photos of
children hitting soldiers and people
attacking Israeli tanks with stones
that responded with fire. In this
situation, the Arabs never created a
paramilitary organization with a great
religious character that tried to take
control of the
Palestinian resistance that at that time was in
power of the
PLO. The PLO was an organization with more
political than religious character. But what
happened to them? In
1988, the PLO proclaimed the declaration of
independence of Palestine without the
UN recognizing it. The president of this
organization, Yasser Arafat, recognized the
state of Israel in an official letter
sent to the Israeli Prime Minister and
in response, Israel recognized the PLO
as the legitimate representative of the
Palestinian people, thus beginning the
Oslo accords and the Palestinian national authority.
This authority recognized the
right of  Palestinians to
govern themselves in Gaza and cis
Jordan but again peace was not
established between both peoples and
violence continued and
Jewish settlements in Palestinian territory
as a result in 2000 the
second intifada happened which was much more
violent and bloody than the first with
several attacks in between to this
Israel responded with more repression with
its great ally the United States the
attacks of 11 confronted the
United States against the Arab world even
more so their ties
as allies became stronger
during this intifada that lasted several
years the Palestinian leader Yasser
Arafat died and that meant the rise of never
more radicalizing the
conflict as a result of the second
intifada in 2005 Israeli civilians
withdrew from the Gaza Strip and
eliminated several of their settlements
from the West Bank there they had
thousands of Israeli soldiers to give
protection to only 8000 Jewish settlers
surrounded by more than a million
Palestinians never became very strong in
the Gaza Strip So Israel withdrew
its  men and built a
separation barrier a wall of more than 700 km to
isolate them and prevent them from ever
obtaining more weapons although we must not
forget that Israel continued to control
its airspace land border and
coast and this subjected the strip to a
shortage of supplies that
impeded its
development this withdrawal of Israel was
taken advantage of by never to take credit for
that victory thanks to its
armed resistance and thanks to this victory they
won the elections of
2006 in the internal struggle for power
the two Arab political parties
Hamas and Alfat began to confront each other
in June 2007 the
low level clashes between these two parties
turned into a local war with
massacres on both sides the dispute would
end with never controlling the
Gaza Strip and Alfat controlling cis
Jordan with the support of the
Madrid quartet this same year to weaken
never Israel and Egypt decreed a harsh
blockade on the Gaza Strip
preventing all steps and the
export of most
products including some basic ones the
inhabitants and the merchandise could only
enter and leave in dribs and drabs what  It
led Gazans to feel like
prisoners in the open air
approximately one and a half million
Palestinians from Gaza survived at that
time on humanitarian aid and
smuggling through a network of
tunnels on the border with
Egypt after six months of truce between
never and Israel in response to the
continuity of the blockade and the
humanitarian crisis never broke the truce and
began to launch rockets against Israel
thus they entered a cycle of
violent conflicts such as those highlighted in 2008
2012 and 2014 the deaths in these
conflicts were many in the
2014 conflict more than 2000 people mostly
civilians died in Gaza while
on the Israeli side six civilians and
soldiers died Israel found itself surrounded
by countries that wanted to attack it
however They had a strong state
with a good army and a good
economic position since its
independence it tried to reduce the
presence of the Palestinians But why
was the Israeli state so powerful and with
many fewer men it achieves so many
victories Well on the one hand it is the country
that receives the most military aid from the United
States along with Ukraine on the other hand it
is important  their training since
military service there is mandatory from the
age of 18 for both women and
men and we cannot
forget one of their best weapons
in recent years, the Iron Dome,
a defense system designed to
intercept and destroy rockets and
missiles launched at it. The system detects
the projectile and responds by firing a
missile at it, preventing it from falling on its
territory. On October 7, 2023,
while the Israelis were
celebrating their own party,
armed groups never launched an attack
against Israel from the Gaza Strip
known as the Alaxa flood. The
surprise attack began early in the
morning of that day with at least 3,000
missiles against Israel and
vehicle-borne incursions into its territory.
Almost 2,000 Palestinian militants
crossed the Gaz Barrier into Israel, they
attacked military bases and massacred
civilians in neighboring Israeli communities. I'm
sure you all remember the
images of that day at the
Re music festival. While the
festival was taking place, alarms were triggered by
falling missiles. Some of the
attackers arrived in  paragliders
while others arrived armed in
pickup trucks or motorcycles with insignia
the group
never fired indiscriminately
at the public sowing chaos the
militants never captured hostages
unleashing a new war full of
violence that continues to this day took
Israel by surprise but it responded
with bombings and the subsequent invasion
of the Gaza Strip Again the
aerial bombardments and
ground offensives by the Israeli forces ar
more than 20,000 Palestinians according to
the Ministry of Health in Gaza a
third of whom were children
for this reason it was heavily criticized by
many organizations because Israel
had violated international
humanitarian law by among other things
carrying out indiscriminate attacks that did not
distinguish between civilians and
military targets and destroying thousands of
Palestinian homes in addition the
Israeli government also cut off all
supplies to Gaza including
food
water fuel and medicine
medical personnel also suffered attacks in the area
on December 23 a total of 36
hospitals had been forced to
close due to damage and lack
of electricity the organization  The World
Health Organization reported that 600 patients and
medical staff had been
killed in attacks targeting
medical facilities on the other hand if we move
to Lebanon the Lebanese group Ebola fired
guided rockets and straight artillery
at Israeli-held positions in
the Golan Heights on October 8
2023 The day after the Greatest
Ever attack the Israeli government
retaliated with drone strikes
and artillery fire at
Ebola positions near the border
between the Golan Heights and Lebanon
the attacks came after
Ebola expressed support and praise for
Ebola's attacks against Israel
subsequently the clashes
intensified
the last decade has left nothing but
clashes in this area the
prospect of Palestine
obtaining a state of its own seems distant at
present the offensive continues with each passing day
more violent leaving us
terrible images of victims of this war that
for now does not seem to have an end
[Music]
near Don't forget to subscribe and give a
Like if you liked it And you can also
follow us on our social networks
Facebook Twitter and Instagram until the
next video